Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/deebanchandran (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Teamwork

Leadership

Python (Programming Language)

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Malay (Full Professional)

Tamil (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

High Achievers Scholarship Award 2014

Data Analyst

Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia (SPM)

Certificate of Higher Education in Science

Honors-Awards

First Prize - Sustainable
Development - Poster Competition WattEX

High Achiever's Scholarship

Deeban Chandran

Associate Consultant (Financial Services) - Data Scientist | MSc Data Science and Business Analytics (Ongoing)

Batu Caves

Summary

Deeban Chandran is a Data Scientist at CADS. Deeban has over 2 years industry experience in the data Science field. Currently undertaking MSc in Data Science and Business Analytics. Possesses an MEng in Petroleum Engineering. Expertise in Microsoft Office, Python, R, Matlab, SQL. Certified as a Data Analyst from Data Star Program by the Centre of Applied Data Science (CADS).

His immense interest in the Data Science sector and ability to apply put the gained knowledge to the proper application has been portrayed through his Research Project on Petrophysical Facies Classification for Reservoir Modelling using Machine Learning Approach.

Experience

Capgemini
Associate Consultant
October 2021 - Present (3 months)
Malaysia

General Assembly Malaysia Teaching Assistant June 2021 - Present (7 months) Malaysia

1. Python Programming. (Assisting the lead instructor in facilitating the inaugural python class in Malaysia by GA)

The Center of Applied Data Science Data Scientist August 2021 - November 2021 (4 months) Malaysia

PETRONAS

Data Scientist

September 2019 - August 2021 (2 years)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- 1. Worked on Time Series Forecasting, tree based machine learning algorithms, and neural networks.
- 2. Carried out data engineering, data cleaning, preprocessing and feature engineering in R.
- 3. Created APIs of forecasting model, optimisation models using pyomo(python)
- 4. Created Rest end pt APIs using flask
- 5. Worked on creating a GUI using matlab
- 6. Worked on web apps and virtual machine
- 7. Coached a group of interns in building an interactive data extraction tool.
- 8. coached a group of Citizen Data Scientist on a simple classification Machine Learning Project.

Oculus Ventures

Co-Founder

May 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Malaysia

Founder of Oculus Ventures.

An information technology company that creates consumer mobile-friendly applications to solve day to day problems faced by the general public.

The Center of Applied Data Science Data Analyst Trainee (DATA STAR) July 2019 - August 2019 (2 months)

Malaysia

- 1. Data Driven Organisation
- 2. Introduction to Programming
- 2. Phyton Programming
- 3. R Programming
- 4. Relational Database Management System (RDMS) SQLite
- 5. SQL
- 6. NoSQL Databases MongoDB
- 7. Statistics Probability & Distribution
- 8. Hypothesis and Statistical Testing
- 9. Visualisation, Storytelling & Effective Communications
- 10. Big Data and Hadoop Ecosystem

NGLTech Group Summer Intern June 2018 - August 2018 (3 months) Malaysia

- 1. Respond to customer and supplier inquiries about order status, changes, or cancellations.
- 2. Contact suppliers to schedule or expedite deliveries and to resolve shortages, missed or late deliveries, and other problems.
- 3. Review requisition order to verify accuracy, terminology, and specifications.
- 4. Prepare, maintain, and review purchasing files, reports and price lists, using word processing, spreadsheet, database, or presentation software.
- 5. Track the status of requisitions, contracts, and orders.
- Check shipments on arrival to ensure that orders have been filled correctly and that goods meet specifications
- 7. Assist the Process Engineer to carry out modifications, experiments and research on a pilot plant that was to be used in an upcoming project.

NGLTech Group Intern June 2016 - August 2016 (3 months) Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- 1. Respond to customer and supplier inquiries about order status, changes, or cancellations.
- 2. Contact suppliers to schedule or expedite deliveries and to resolve shortages, missed or late deliveries, and other problems.
- 3. Review requisition order to verify accuracy, terminology, and specifications.
- 4. Prepare, maintain, and review purchasing files, reports and price lists, using word processing, spreadsheet, database, or presentation software.
- 5. Track the status of requisitions, contracts, and orders.
- 6. Check shipments on arrival to ensure that orders have been filled correctly and that goods meet specifications
- 7. Assist the Process Engineer to carry out modifications, experiments and research on a pilot plant that was to be used in an upcoming project.

Education

Asia Pacific University of Technology and Innovation (APU / APIIT)

Msc, Data Science and Business Analytics · (January 2021 - January 2023)

Heriot-Watt University

Master's degree, Petroleum Engineering · (2015 - 2019)

Heriot-Watt University

Foundation degree, Engineering Science · (2014 - 2015)